Guide to Miscellaneous Financial Materials Concerning Lumber Companies Operating in the North American West
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Miscellaneous financial materials concerning lumber companies operating in the North American West
1902-1949
Ndy75
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.42
(2 boxes)
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning lumber and timber companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include company correspondence, bondholders' agreements, letters to the stock- and bondholders, advertisements, balance sheets, mortgage and trust indentures, reorganization plans, reports, stock offerings, and trust agreements. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Most of these financial materials were part of a collection acquired by Yale in 1922 from William H. Brown of West Haven, Conn. The collection, initially called the William H. Brown Statistical Library, numbered some 23,000 documents and covered the years 1890 to 1917. The collection was merged with similar materials already in the University Library and later expanded by gifts from Brown and others to become what is now known as the William H. Brown Collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning lumber and timber companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include company correspondence, bondholders' agreements, letters to the stock- and bondholders, advertisements, balance sheets, mortgage and trust indentures, reorganization plans, reports, stock offerings, and trust agreements. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Arrangement
Files are arranged first by region, i.e. Canada and the United States, and then alphabetically by company name.
Lumber trade -- West (U.S.); Lumber trade -- Canada, Western; Trust indentures -- Specimens.; Financial statements -- Specimens.; William H. Brown Collection
- Canadian Puget Sound Lumber Company, Limited, 1911; Ndy75 C1 +C16; (4 documents) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Empire Lumber Company, 1926-1931; Ndy75 C1 +Em7; (3 documents) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Calaveras Timber Company, 1928; Ndy75 U2 +C125; (2 documents) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Harbor Plywood Corporation, 1947-1949; Ndy75 U2 +H214; (9 documents) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Kirby-Bonner Lumber Company, 1920; Ndy75 U2 +K63; (2 documents) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Kirby Lumber Company, 1901-1922; Ndy75 U2 +K64; (16 documents) (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
- Long-Bell Lumber Company, 1907-1942; Ndy75 U2 +L85; (10 documents) (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
- Long-Bell Lumber Corporation, 1924-1934; Ndy75 U2 +L86; (3 documents) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Rayonier Inc., 1937; Ndy75 U2 +R218; (1 document) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- C.A. Smith Timber Company, 1912; Ndy75 U2 +Sm5; (2 documents) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Weyerhaeuser Timber Company, 1047?, 1949?; Ndy75 U2 +W544; (2 documents) (Box 2, Folder 7)